Guide to the Transgender Oral History Project Zine Distro Project Papers, 1992-2013 and undated RL.11033
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Transgender Oral History Project zine distro project papers
1992-2013 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Transgender Oral History Project. Trans Oral History Project
RL.11033
0.6 Linear Feet 2 upright hollinger boxes (56 items)
The collection comprises 35 trans-inclusive zines gathered and distributed by the Transgender Oral History Project beginning in 2012, along with an informational folder for the project. The zines date from 1992-2013 or are undated. The majority feature single-issues, in only a few instances are there duplicate copies of an issue. Topics include the politics of patriarchy, sexuality, being queer; gender issues; developmental issues for adolescents and youths identifying as queer or trans; transitioning; instruction for children and allies, including use of pronouns; and the history of the Transgender Oral History Project.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by title.
Historical Note
The Transgender Oral History Project (also known as the Trans Oral History Project) was founded in 2009 and is a community-driven effort to collect and share a diverse range of stories from within the transgender and gender-variant communities. It promotes grassroots media projects, documents trans people’s experiences, maintains a publicly accessible digital archive, and teaches media production skills. In 2012, the organization started to gather and distribute zines by creating a "distro to promote trans-inclusive zines in order to increase access to stories within the trans community."
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
The collection comprises 35 trans-inclusive zines gathered and distributed by the Transgender Oral History Project beginning in 2012, along with an informational folder for the project. The zines date from 1992-2013 or are undated. The majority feature single-issues, in only a few instances are there duplicate copies of an issue. Topics include the politics of patriarchy, sexuality, being queer; gender issues; developmental issues for adolescents and youths identifying as queer or trans; transitioning; instruction for children and allies, including use of pronouns; and the history of the Transgender Oral History Project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Transgender Oral History Project Zine Distro Project Papers were was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2013.
Transgender Oral History Project; Transgenderism; Transgenderism -- Education; Transgenderism -- United States; Transgenderism -- Periodicals; Transgenderism -- Political aspects; Gender identity -- Political aspects; Transgender people -- Identity; Transgender people -- Periodicals; Transgender people -- Social conditions; Transgender people -- United States; Transgender youth -- United States; Transgender youth -- Social conditions; Sexual minority youth -- United States; Sexual minorities -- Political activity -- United States; United States -- Social conditions -- 1990-; Fanzines; Transgender Oral History Project. Trans Oral History Project
- Information folder, 2012
  - Transgender Oral History Project informational leaflets, 2012; 7 items (Box 1)
- Zines, 1992-2013 and undated
  - 20 Holes in September, 2011; 1 items (Box 1)
  - Becoming-woman & I have even met happy drag queens, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Bound to struggle, #1-5, 2010-2011; 10 items (Box 1)
  - Carly: She's still my daddy, 2004; 1 items (Box 1)
  - Community in transition: 40 years of struggle, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Every body is a modified body, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Excerpts from a journal of a trans-girl, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Femme a barbe, #2-3, 2 items (Box 1)
  - The Five Sexes, 1 items (Box 1)
  - A font by any other name, 2013; 1 items (Box 1)
  - Genderfailz, #1-2, 2009; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Gender matters, 2012; 1 items (Box 1)
  - The gender neutral bathroom challenge & Strategies towards trans celebration, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Hey lady, #2-4, 3 items (Box 1)
  - Hidden expressions, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Interview with Bet Power, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Just so you know, #2, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Learning good consent, 1 items (Box 1)
  - Militant flamboyance, 2009; 1 items (Box 1)
  - Out of order: Queer and trans youth resistance, 1 items (Box 2)
  - Out of the closets and into the libraries, 1 items (Box 2)
  - Queers read this, 2990; 1 items (Box 2)
  - Sex testing and the Olympics: A history, 2009; 1 items (Box 2)
  - So you want to be an ally!, 1 items (Box 2)
  - Sometimes things get confusing when you're mentally ill, 1 items (Box 2)
  - Supermarket supermodel, 1 items (Box 2)
  - Tim tum, 3 items (Box 2)
  - Tracing this body & New flesh, new struggles, 2003; 1 items (Box 2)
  - Trannydykewhore, 1 items (Box 2)
  - The transgender herb garden, 2009; 1 items (Box 2)
  - Transgender liberation: A movement whose time has come, 1992; 1 items (Box 2)
  - Transphobia: Let's stop it, 2013; 1 items (Box 2)
  - Unapologetic, #3, 2002; 1 items (Box 2)
  - Vanguard revisited, 2011; 1 items (Box 2)